<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Words &amp; Code</title>
    <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Words &amp; Code</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 23:21:27 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Flutter Web and Rive Animation Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/flutter_rive_tutorial/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2022 23:21:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/flutter_rive_tutorial/</guid>
      <description>Here is a beginner to intermediate tutorial for setting up a Flutter web app with Rive animations. I recently built a sliding tile game that incorporates Rive animations for the Flutter Hackathon. In this tutorial I’m going to show you how to add an animation to your Flutter web app and control it through user input.
We will create a basketball animation that will get triggered each time the user clicks on a button.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Your Guide to Arch Linux</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/arch_linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Mar 2021 00:22:09 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/arch_linux/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! This guide is meant to take you through the process of setting up Arch Linux. It&amp;rsquo;s more of a set of guidelines rather than strict procedure. I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to give new or potential users an idea of what it&amp;rsquo;s like to dual boot your computer with Arch Linux.
I started using Arch in 2018 after getting tired of Ubuntu and since then I have dealt with my fair share of problems (corrupted ISO, problematic updates, bluetooth nightmares).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to start contributing to open source</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/open_source/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 02:14:58 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/open_source/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! Recently I made my first open source contribution and wanted to share my experience as well as any tips I have for developers getting into open source development.
Step 1 — Finding motivation Due to COVID-19, I realized how much we rely on technology to bring people together. Then I thought about how much of that tech is made possible due to open source. I feel so grateful that I have access to and the potential to contribute to all this tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A-Z Tech to be thankful for in 2020</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/thanksgiving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 20:46:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/thanksgiving/</guid>
      <description>Hi everyone! This Thanksgiving my mom did an activity with her grade 2’s where they went around their virtual classroom listing things they were thankful for from A-Z. This inspired me to write my very first Medium article on technologies that I’m thankful for this Thanksgiving :) These range from tech I’ve used to tech I am interested in using in the future.
AWS I started using Amazon’s web services earlier this year to host a project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Co-op</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/getting_started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 02:31:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/post/getting_started/</guid>
      <description>Since my co-op starts next week I thought it would be the perfect time to set up my blog so I can document my experiences. I hope I can capture what I learn every week and reflect on my time as an intern. Maybe in a year I will be showing this to the new set of co-ops.
My First Day at Bell I left my house early like any responsible employee on their first day of work and arrived more than half an hour early.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://gucci-ninja.github.io/wordsandcode/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Suhavi Sandhu, but my online name is usually gucci-ninja. My pronouns are she/her. I&amp;rsquo;m a software engineer in Toronto, currently working at Guidewire, where I work on building scalable and robust infrastructure. On this blog I usually talk about my personal projects and tech-related topics that I find interesting.
I graduated with a software engineering degree in 2020 and since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to find my place in the tech community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
